<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<result><name>     Exhibit 1.     Empirical Studies of Assets and Liabilities of Low-Income Households   </name><data><row0 is_array="true"><item>Author</item><item>Data Source</item><item>Sample/       Study Population</item><item>Method</item><item>Outcomes Analyzed</item><item>Key Explanatory Variables</item><item>Findings</item><item>Authors Principal Conclusions</item></row0><row1 is_array="true"><item>Aizcorbe, Kennickell, &amp;amp; Moore (2003)</item><item>1998, 2001 SCF.</item><item>U.S. families ("primary economic units" that include families and other       persons in the household).</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Net worth, assets, liabilities, credit card balances, &amp;amp; debt to income       ratio.</item><item>Percentile of income, age, education, race/ethnicity, work status, region,       &amp;amp; home ownership.</item><item>Assets and net worth skewed toward the wealthy. Growth in assets and       net worth flat during early 1990s, accelerated during late 1990s.</item><item>(1) Median and mean net worth of families grew substantially between       1998 and 2001. (2) Ownership of homes and financial assets grew. (3) Debt       holding and debt levels increased.</item></row1><row2 is_array="true"><item>Badu, Daniels, &amp;amp; Salandro (1999)</item><item>1992 SCF.</item><item>Families with a black or white head.</item><item>(1) Instrumental variables regression  the model measures       the difference in net worth between blacks and whites. (2) Canonical correlation       analysis  measures the differences in asset and liability holdings       of blacks versus whites.</item><item>Net worth, financial assets, portfolio composition, &amp;amp; use of credit.</item><item>Control variables capture income, age, education, employment, race, marital       status, children health, and pension.</item><item>(1) White households have significantly greater net worth and financial       assets than black households. (2) The authors find no evidence that the net       worth of black households is constrained by barriers to obtaining credit.       (3) There is evidence that blacks are more risk averse in their asset choices,       and that they pay higher interest rates.</item><item>(1) Both blacks and whites rely a great deal on credit cards. (2) According       to the canonical correlation analysis, blacks do not on average have any       assets that are independent of liabilities. (3) Whites are more risk tolerant       than blacks. (4) On average both whites and blacks' principal asset is their       vehicle.</item></row2><row3 is_array="true"><item>Belsky &amp;amp; Calder (2004)</item><item>2001 SCF.</item><item>U.S. families.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Financial assets, non-financial tangible assets, debt.</item><item>Age, race, income.</item><item>(1) Median net wealth of the lowest income quintile is less than one-quarter       of the median wealth of the second income quintile. (2) The most commonly       held financial asset for individuals in the bottom income quintile is the       transaction account. (3) The most commonly held non-financial asset for       individuals in the bottom income quintile is the automobile.</item><item>(1) Minorities in the lowest income quintile have much lower rates of       asset ownership than whites in the same income quintile. (2) A large share       of families in the lowest income quintile are operating in a cash economy,       preventing them from accessing mainstream, long-term credit. (3) Access to       debt is similar for whites and nonwhites in the lowest income quintile.</item></row3><row4 is_array="true"><item>Browning &amp;amp; Lusardi (1996)</item><item>Literature review includes SCF, CES, PSID, HRS, AHEAD, SIPP, NLS, RHS.</item><item>U.S. Households</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Household saving.</item><item>Various demographic variables in many different surveys; models used       to describe household saving behavior.</item><item>(1) A "standard optimizing framework," integrating the CEQ model and       standard additive model for consumption decisions can provide an adequate       framework for examining household saving. (2) Though current datasets provide       an accurate portrait of who saves over time, they are less effective in       explaining why people save.</item><item>(1) More and "better" data are needed to examine the question of why       households save, including more information on health status, perception       of mortality risk, the situation of children, and liquidity constraints.       (2) Simulation models that explore both observed and difficult-to-measure       heterogeneity variables across populations could shed more light on the savings       decision. These models could also be linked to the standard model, which       could integrate a larger range of life-cycle decisions.</item></row4><row5 is_array="true"><item>Bucks, Kennickell, &amp;amp; Moore (2006)</item><item>1995, 1998, 2001, 2004 SCF.</item><item>U.S. families ("primary economic units" that include families and other       persons in the household).</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Net worth, assets, liabilities, credit card balances, &amp;amp; debt to income       ratio.</item><item>Percentile of income, age, education, race/ethnicity, work status, region,       &amp;amp; home ownership.</item><item>Assets and net worth skewed toward the wealthy. Financial assets comprised       a smaller proportion of portfolios than in 2001. Despite lower interest rates       in 2004 than in 2001, there were moderate increases in debt burden.</item><item>(1) Despite small changes in income between 2001 and 2004, there were       some increases in mean (6.3%) and median (1.5%) net worth that pale in comparison       to the increases between 1998 and 2001. (2) Real estate values increased       sharply between 2001 and 2004. (3) The rise in debt use is attributable to       the increased use of real estate debt.</item></row5><row6 is_array="true"><item>Caner &amp;amp; Wolff (2004)</item><item>1984-99 PSID.</item><item>U.S. families.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Asset poverty rates.</item><item>Race, age, education, tenure, family type.</item><item>(1) Nonwhites are more than twice as likely as whites to be asset poor,       though the nonwhite asset poverty rate declined from 1984-1999. (2) From       1994-99, asset poverty rates increased for most age groups. (3) Asset poverty       rates decrease with higher education levels. (4) Changes in race/ethnicity       and family type had a negligible effect on the overall poverty rate.</item><item>Though the traditional income poverty measure decreased over the 1984-99       period that the authors examined, the asset poverty rate barely changed and       the severity of poverty increased.</item></row6><row7 is_array="true"><item>Carasso, Bell, Olsen, &amp;amp; Steuerle (2005)</item><item>CPS, SCF, various years.</item><item>U.S. households and families.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Homeownership rates, homeownership subsidies and tax expenditures.</item><item>Income, education, race, children in family, marital status.</item><item>(1) Homeownership rates increased from 1990-2003, but this is mostly       just catch up from losses in the 80s. (2) Homeownership rates for minorities       and less educated individuals are significantly lower than for whites and       more educated groups. (3) Federal housing subsidies and tax expenditures       are unevenly distributed in a "U" shape.</item><item>Future policies need to smooth the "U"-shaped distribution by changing       ownership incentives for low- and middle-class families.</item></row7><row8 is_array="true"><item>Domowitz &amp;amp; Sartain (1999)</item><item>Proprietary data of 827 bankruptcy filers and the 1983 SCF.</item><item>U.S. bankruptcy filers and matched non-filers.</item><item>Nested logit model relating the probability of filing for bankruptcy       to household demographic and financial characteristics.</item><item>Bankruptcy choice (yes/no).</item><item>Medical debts above 2% of annual income, homeownership, marital status,       debts/assets, credit card balance/income, secured and unsecured debts/income.</item><item>(1) The effect of marriage on bankruptcy is statistically negligible       (p. 410). (2) Debtors without homes are almost seven times more likely to       file than the average homeowner (p. 413). (3) An increase in credit card       debt to the level of an average chapter 7 debtor is predicted to cause a       624% increase in the probability of filing for bankruptcy (p. 414).</item><item>(1) Substantial medical debt is found to be the most important factor       in assessing the impact of household conditions (p. 419). (2) On the margin,       the largest single contribution to bankruptcy is credit card debt (p. 419).       (3) Homeownership discourages bankruptcy by a substantial amount (p. 410).</item></row8><row9 is_array="true"><item>Fay, Hurst, &amp;amp; White (2002)</item><item>PSID.</item><item>U.S. households.</item><item>Probit regressions- measuring the determinants of filing for bankruptcy.</item><item>Bankruptcy.</item><item>Financial benefits of applying for bankruptcy, debts, nonexempt assets,       local bankruptcy rate, income, education, family size.</item><item>(1) Far fewer households file for bankruptcy than the number that would       actually benefit from filing (p. 712). (2) Debts, when financial benefits       from filing for bankruptcy are greater than zero, are a more important       contributors for the filing decision than foregone nonexempt assets (p. 716).       (3) Education, income, and homeownership (marginally) have the predicted       effects on the decision to file for bankruptcy (p. 713). (4) Surprisingly,       business owners are less likely to file for bankruptcy (p. 713). (5) Finally,       individuals living in districts where bankruptcy is more prevalent are more       likely to file for bankruptcy (p. 706).</item><item>(1) The authors find support for the notion that households are more       likely to file for bankruptcy when their financial benefit from filing is       higher (p. 706). (2) Their model predicts that a $1,000 increase in the benefit       from filing for bankruptcy results in a 7% increase in the number of bankruptcy       filings (p. 715). (3) They also conclude that the argument that households       file for bankruptcy in times of extreme duress is not supported by the data       (p. 706).</item></row9><row10 is_array="true"><item>Gross &amp;amp; Souleles (2002)</item><item>Panel dataset of credit card accounts from several credit card issuers.       Representative of all open accounts in 1995. Contains other financial information       and spans from 1995-1997.</item><item>U.S. credit card holders in 1995.</item><item>Duration models.</item><item>Default and bankruptcy.</item><item>Credit score, employment, credit use, age, lack of health insurance,       &amp;amp; regional home prices.</item><item>Risk controls (credit scores) were highly significant in predicting       bankruptcy and delinquency. Even controlling for credit scores, accounts       with larger balances and purchase or smaller payments were also more likely       to default. Unemployment and lack of health insurance also increased default,       but these variables only explain a small part of the change in bankruptcy       and delinquency rates over the sample period (p. 345).</item><item>Ceteris paribus, a credit card holder in 1997 was 1% more likely to declare       bankruptcy and 3% more likely to be delinquent on payments than cardholders       with an identical profile in 1995. This magnitude is almost as large as if       the whole population of cardholders became one standard deviation riskier       in terms of credit scores. These results are consistent with a demand effect.       That is, it is likely that the costs of defaulting or filing for bankruptcy       decreased between 1995 and 1997 (p. 322).</item></row10><row11 is_array="true"><item>Himmelstein et al. (2005)</item><item>Dataset of 1,771 bankruptcy filers in five federal courts in 2001.</item><item>U.S. bankruptcy filers.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Bankruptcy.</item><item>Medical reasons for filing bankruptcy, such as illness or injury, uncovered       medical bills, lapse of insurance coverage, or death of a family member.</item><item>(1) The average debtor tends to be middle-aged, working or middle class,       with children and at least some college education. (2) Nearly half the debtors       surveyed had a "major medical bankruptcy." (3) A lapse in health insurance       is a strong predictor of a medical bankruptcy.</item><item>Four major deficiencies in the "financial safety net" for families       confronting illness  (1) lapses in insurance; (2) underinsurance       in the face of serious illness; (3) lack of comprehensive employment-based       coverage; and (4) lack of adequate disability insurance and paid sick leave       for most families  warrant broad policy reforms regarding medical       and social insurance.</item></row11><row12 is_array="true"><item>Kennickell (2000)</item><item>1989-1998 SCF.</item><item>SCF families and related response variables.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Comparisons across different SCF datasets.</item><item>Net worth, response rates, sample types.</item><item>(1) Complex tax situations, varying rates of return, omitted asset income,       and geographic distribution detrimentally affect the SCF list sample. (2)       Unit nonresponse in the survey has become worse since at least 1992. (3)       Interviewer and respondent errors indicate that survey instruments warrant       further improvement.</item><item>(1) A "less noisy stratification" of the list sample can be achieved       using multiple years of SOI data. (2) New research tools, interviewer incentives,       and survey cooperation should be used to address the problem of unit nonresponse.       (3) Further research should be dedicated to the area of instrument design       and the imputation of missing data.</item></row12><row13 is_array="true"><item>Kennickell (2003)</item><item>1989-2001 SCF.</item><item>U.S. families.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Distribution of and shifts of wealth holdings.</item><item>Net worth, financial and non-financial assets, debts, equity.</item><item>(1) Roughly 1/3 of total wealth is held by the highest 1%, the next 9%,       and the remaining 90% of the wealth distribution. (2) Wealth levels of the       baby boomers trended upward during the 1989-2001 period. (3) Median wealth       of white non-Hispanics was 6.4 times that of African Americans in 2001. This       has decreased from a factor of 18.5 in 1989. A substantial portion of African       American families had "middle class" net worth in 2001.</item><item>(1) Changes in financial services and economic structures have contributed       to a variety of changes in the wealth distribution. (2) Leverage declines       sharply with wealth. (3) Analysis of portfolio structure and institutional       relationships would be helpful given the changes in the available set of       financial services.</item></row13><row14 is_array="true"><item>Kennickell &amp;amp; Sundén (1997)</item><item>1989 and 1992 SCF.</item><item>U.S. families.</item><item>(1) Descriptive. (2) OLS and robust regressions.</item><item>The effect of Social Security and other pension wealth on non-pension       net worth.</item><item>Pension wealth, Social Security wealth, net worth.</item><item>(1) Including Social Security and pension wealth in the SCF measurement       of net worth makes the net worth distribution more even. (2) Defined benefit       plan coverage has a negative effect on non-pension net worth, while the effect       of defined contribution plans and Social Security wealth is insignificant.</item><item>(1) While there has been a shift over time from defined benefit to defined       contribution plans, workers do not seem to be contributing as much to the       latter. (2) The insignificant effect of Social Security on saving may reflect       households' uncertainty concerning the level of future Social Security benefits.</item></row14><row15 is_array="true"><item>Lupton &amp;amp; Smith (1999)</item><item>HRS and 1984, 1989, and 1994 PSID.</item><item>U.S. households.</item><item>(1) Descriptive. (2) Multivariate OLS estimates of household savings.</item><item>Household saving.</item><item>Marital status, composition of wealth, sex, net worth, family income,       race, age.</item><item>(1) Wealth distribution is skewed more than income distribution. (2)       Net worth varies across marital status, with marital disparities being much       larger among minorities. (3) The typical married couple has more social security       wealth than personal net worth. (4) Savings between PSID waves are significantly       lower among not married households. Savings differences between married and       not married households are largest in the "earliest duration" in marital       states and then tend to converge. (5) Children do not explain why married       families save more.</item><item>There is a "quantitatively large" relationship between saving and marriage.       The duration of the marriage, furthermore, positively affects wealth. The       initial savings of married households contributes to the large wealth gap       between married and not married households.</item></row15><row16 is_array="true"><item>McKernan &amp;amp; Chen (2005)</item><item>1998 SCF.</item><item>Business owners.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Small business and microenterprise programs and participation.</item><item>Age, firm size, net worth, race, sex, education, household income.</item><item>American small business owners tend to be male, white, have at least       a high school education, and have moderate incomes. While anecdotal evidence       suggests that small business grants and microenterprise programs increase       entrepreneurship, studies that applied more stringent controls (for selection       bias, for example) found no increase in wage rates or employment due to grants       for these programs, but did find decreases in the length of unemployment       spells.</item><item>(1) More research is needed to evaluate whether small business and       microenterprise programs increase self-sufficiency. (2) Policies should consider       self-sufficiency and economic development goals separately. (3) Standards       and accreditation for programs should be created by foundations and policymakers.       (4) Metrics for measuring success should be further developed. (5) Barriers       that limit at-risk groups should be considered. (6) Small business and       microenterprise should be evaluated against other programs with similar       objectives.</item></row16><row17 is_array="true"><item>Shapiro (2004)</item><item>Qualitative data from in-depth interviews, SIPP, PSID.</item><item>In-depth interview sample of 200 poor to middle-class families with       school-age children in Boston, LA, and St. Louis.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Receipt of transfer or financial assistance, effects of transfer/financial       assistance.</item><item>Race.</item><item>(1) Sizable inheritances and inter vivos gifts can give young families       a "head start" (ex: Allows home purchase in neighborhood with good schools).       (2) Whites are more likely than blacks to receive sizable transfers. (3)       Families with assets are able to acquire high-quality education for their       children, and their education can transfer their economic advantages to their       children.</item><item>Transfer of "transformative assets" perpetuates inequality.</item></row17><row18 is_array="true"><item>Smith (1995)</item><item>HRS</item><item>U.S. households.</item><item>(1) Descriptive. (2) Multivariate OLS estimates of net worth using the       HRS.</item><item>Comparisons of major asset surveys; racial, ethnic and other disparities       in the distribution of net worth.</item><item>Race, age, education, income, region, health status, and other demographic       variables.</item><item>(1) Missing values in surveys are much larger among the financial and       real asset categories. (2) In the HRS, the distribution of wealth is severely       skewed  mean net worth is 2.4 times the median. (3) The average       middle-aged black or Hispanic household has no liquid assets at their disposal.</item><item>(1) Compared to other surveys, the quality of HRS asset data is high,       although nonresponses remain a problem. (2) Racial disparities in the HRS       are mainly due to differential inheritances across generations, lower minority       incomes, poorer health, and a very narrow definition of wealth that       systematically excludes Social Security and employer pensions.</item></row18><row19 is_array="true"><item>Smith (1999)</item><item>PSID, AHEAD, HRS.</item><item>U.S. households.</item><item>(1) Descriptive. (2) Ordered probit models of self-reported health status       by income and wealth. (3) OLS models of new chronic health problems on household       wealth.</item><item>Health and economic status.</item><item>Self-reported health status, income, wealth (models included also control       for race, sex, age, marital status and education).</item><item>(1) Across all age groups, those in excellent health have more wealth       than other respondents. Changes in health over time are also associated with       wealth changes. (2) Out-of-pocket medical costs are relatively small for       the average person. Despite these relatively low costs, the impact of new       severe health problems on savings produces a mean wealth reduction of 7%.       (3) There is a steep inverse relationship between employment grade and poor       health outcomes.</item><item>(1) For middle to older age groups, there are significant effects of       new health events on income and wealth, though this may not be true for earlier       ages. (2) Though economic resources impact health outcomes, this direction       of causality may be most pronounced during childhood and early adulthood.</item></row19><row20 is_array="true"><item>Stavins (2000)</item><item>1998 SCF.</item><item>U.S. families.</item><item>(1) Descriptive. (2) Logit regressions  measuring the likelihood       of bill payment delinquency or prior bankruptcy filing.</item><item>Bankruptcy, bill payment delinquency.</item><item>Age, homeownership, income, net worth, unemployment, family size, marital       status, number of credit cards, credit card balance, debt/income ratio.</item><item> </item><item>(1) The strongest factors increasing the probability of being behind       on bill payments were previously filing for bankruptcy and being unemployed       at any time in the last 12 months. Past bankruptcy filing increases the       probability of having delinquent loans whether or not bankruptcy filing was       recent or 10+ years ago (p. 24). (2) Households with higher unpaid credit       card balances are more likely to have filed for bankruptcy in the past (p.       25).</item></row20><row21 is_array="true"><item>Sullivan (2004)</item><item>SIPP</item><item>Single women.</item><item>Descriptive</item><item>Vehicle ownership &amp;amp; vehicle equity.</item><item>Children-Yes/No.</item><item>(1) Families with a high probability of participating in welfare are       more likely to have vehicle equity than any other type of asset. (2) 48%       of all single mothers without a high school diploma own a car.</item><item>(1) Asset restrictions do have an effect on vehicle ownership. (2) Asset       limits have no effect on liquid asset holdings.</item></row21><row22 is_array="true"><item>Wolff (2004)</item><item>1983, 1989, 1992, 1995, 1998 SCF.</item><item>U.S. families.</item><item>Descriptive.</item><item>Distribution of net worth, mean/median net worth, &amp;amp; elements of wealth.</item><item>Income, age, children in family, female-headed family.</item><item>(1) The bottom income quintile does not have the assets to sustain       consumption for any amount of time given an emergency versus 25 months for       those in the highest income quintile. (2) In 1998, poor blacks, on average,       had 1/4 the net worth of poor whites. (3) For the poor, mean net worth fell       by 5% between 1983 and 1998.</item><item>(1) Only the richest 20% experienced large wealth gains between 1983       and 1998. (2) Wealth inequality continued to rise. (3) Overall indebtedness       continues to rise. (4) There continue to be large wealth disparities across       race.</item></row22></data></result>
