<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<result><name>: Table 15</name><data><row0 is_array="true"><item>Case Management    		Definition of Case Management 		  		Case management is a professional practice in which the service recipient 		is a partner, to the greatest extent possible, in assessing needs, defining 		desired outcomes, obtaining services, treatments, and supports, and in preventing 		and managing crisis. 		  		National Association of Case Management (2008)    	Having a central case manager was viewed by service providers and law enforcement 	alike as a critical service not only for victims but for other service providers 	and agencies involved in a trafficking case. In fact, the case manager was 	considered to have a critical role throughout the lifespan of a trafficking 	case, including at initial contact by law enforcement or others, during 	depositions, appearances in court, application renewals for benefits and 	services, and family reunification. 	  	According to respondents, the case manager is responsible for assessing 	clients needs for service and support; identifying, obtaining, and 	coordinating those services for clients; coordinating and managing communications 	across systems involved in a case; and serving as a liaison for the client 	with other agencies. For some clients, the case manager also serves as translator 	or obtains translation services for the clients. Other common responsibilities 	include accompanying clients to appointments, assisting/teaching clients 	to access public transportation, and teaching clients basic life skills. 	The importance of this role is evident in the fact that most of the programs 	in the study reported providing some form of case management as part of their 	menu of services for trafficking victims. However, like with other services, 	providing case management to victims is not without challenges. 	  Ingredients for Effective Case Management  		    Establishing a hopeful relationship with the client; 		    		    Assessing client strengths and needs; 		    		    Developing, in partnership with the client, a service plan to achieve desired 		    outcomes; 		    		    Locating, linking, and following up with needed services and support; 		    		    Monitoring, coordinating, and adjusting services and supports to achieve 		    desired outcomes; 		    		    Providing crisis prevention and intervention services and support; and 		    		    Advocating for the client. 		  		Extracted from the NACM Web site, 		http://www.yournacm.com/definition.html    	Challenges to case management 	  	One of the greatest challenges respondents reported to providing effective 	case management was limited resources. Case management for trafficking victims 	can be a 24/7 responsibility. In fact, providing case management 	to a single client can be a full-time job; although not true for all clients. 	This generally limits the amount of time that a case manager is available 	to other clients and thus necessitates a limited case load for each case 	manager. In contrast, resources to support full-time case managers are scarce. 	In particular, smaller agencies without the kind of back-office 	functions and infrastructure as larger organizations, struggle with funding 	streams like the per capita program. It is difficult for them to keep up 	with the reimbursement process and difficult to support case managers during 	periods when they are not serving any trafficking victims. Large agencies 	on the other hand are able to support case managers under other funding streams 	and often have case managers working with different (victim) populations, 	such as domestic violence victims or refugees. While those in the field, 	including smaller agencies, recognize that the current per capita funding 	is intended to be a more efficient use of limited resources than previous 	funding streams in that it allows for the provision of services to victims 	anytime, anywhere throughout the country, and only reimburses 	providers for services actually provided to victims, not all agencies, including 	those specific to human trafficking, have been able to diversify their funding 	beyond the per capita program. As a result, some agencies have had to move 	to part-time case managers which has limited their ability to be available 	on a 24/7 basis. 	  	When it comes to providing case management services to domestic victims of 	trafficking, domestic victims have to currently rely on case management services 	that may be offered through existing systems and programs, such as the child 	welfare system and domestic violence and youth shelter programs, which are 	often already overburdened and hence struggle with providing effective case 	management to their existing caseload. This significant gap in services for 	domestic trafficking victims is beginning to be addressed. For example, OVC 	recently released an announcement to fund two demonstration programs to provide 	comprehensive services, including case management, to domestic child victims 	of human trafficking, and an evaluation of the demonstrations is being funded 	by the National Institute of Justice. 	  	Another significant challenge or barrier to effective case management is 	the length of service eligibility (e.g., 9 months for pre-certification services 	and 4 months for certification services under the per capita program; 15-, 	30-, and 60-day stays in shelters for runaway and homeless youth). Service 	providers reported that it can take significant time to build trust with 	clients and get them to begin opening up to their case managers. Until this 	happens, getting clients to accept and engage in services can be difficult 	and often times inappropriate. The eligibility time restrictions can limit 	the ability of case managers to move some clients from crisis to 	thriving and toward the accomplishment of their service goals. 	  When working with a domestic victim, I just need more time. 		I cant stabilize a client with extensive trauma histories within 90 		days or transition them to permanent housing within 18-months. Many of my 		clients struggle to get an education (or GED), learn life skills, obtain 		employable skills, and get employed. This is especially true if they have 		not begun to work on trauma recovery and this can take years.  		Service provider    	Working with other service providers and law enforcement is acknowledged 	as a key factor underlying a case managers success in working with 	victims. Limited access to information regarding details of a clients 	case can hinder the role of the case manager. For example, several providers 	reported incidents where case managers were put in difficult situations with 	their clients because they did not have information that the clients thought 	they should have about their legal cases, and in some situations, the results 	of medical tests. When case managers are unable to provide clients with (timely) 	answers to their questions, respondents reported that this creates feelings 	of distrust and can cause set-backs in the victims recovery. 	  	While effective case managers were described by respondents as highly committed 	and dedicated to their work, these same strengths can create another challenge 	to case management; a high turnover rate. Service providers and law enforcement 	reported that case managers working with victims of human trafficking are 	overworked and underpaid, contributing to staff burnout. Additionally, 	respondents pointed to vicarious or secondary trauma and the lack of resources 	to address this for staff as another contributing factor to the burnout and 	high turnover. As one service provider put it, There are few resources 	devoted to helping the helpers.</item><item>Definition of Case Management 		  		Case management is a professional practice in which the service recipient 		is a partner, to the greatest extent possible, in assessing needs, defining 		desired outcomes, obtaining services, treatments, and supports, and in preventing 		and managing crisis. 		  		National Association of Case Management (2008)</item><item>Ingredients for Effective Case Management  		    Establishing a hopeful relationship with the client; 		    		    Assessing client strengths and needs; 		    		    Developing, in partnership with the client, a service plan to achieve desired 		    outcomes; 		    		    Locating, linking, and following up with needed services and support; 		    		    Monitoring, coordinating, and adjusting services and supports to achieve 		    desired outcomes; 		    		    Providing crisis prevention and intervention services and support; and 		    		    Advocating for the client. 		  		Extracted from the NACM Web site, 		http://www.yournacm.com/definition.html</item><item>When working with a domestic victim, I just need more time. 		I cant stabilize a client with extensive trauma histories within 90 		days or transition them to permanent housing within 18-months. Many of my 		clients struggle to get an education (or GED), learn life skills, obtain 		employable skills, and get employed. This is especially true if they have 		not begun to work on trauma recovery and this can take years.  		Service provider</item></row0></data></result>
