<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<result><name>: Table 6</name><data><row0 is_array="true"><item>Legislation</item><item>Main Purpose</item></row0><row1 is_array="true"><item>The Family And Medical Insurance Leave    (FAMILY) Act (2013)</item><item>To provide up to 12 weeks of    two-thirds wage replacement to workers in both large and small    organizations.  To be administered by a new office within the Social Security    Administration; financed by payroll tax on employers and employees of 0.2%.</item></row1><row2 is_array="true"><item>The Federal Employees Paid Parental    Leave Act (2013, 2011, 2009)</item><item>To provide four weeks of paid leave    among the 12 weeks of unpaid leave the FMLA offers, for federal-employee    parents of new children (federal employees do not receive dedicated paid    parental leave).</item></row2><row3 is_array="true"><item>Family Income to Respond to    Significant Transitions (FIRST) (2009)</item><item>To award state grants to expand on    or build programs to provide partial wage replacement for caregiving due to    birth or adoption, or other purposes consistent with the FMLA.</item></row3><row4 is_array="true"><item>The Family Leave Insurance Act    (2009)</item><item>To establish a national fund and    contract with states to establish or expand existing state systems, or    piggy-back on the capacity of the Social Security Administration on state    request.  Would create a national paid family and medical leave insurance    program, allowing for equivalent state and/or private programs.</item></row4><row5 is_array="true"><item>The Healthy Families Act (2013,    2011, 2009)</item><item>To enact a mandate on employers of    15 or more employees to provide up to seven days of paid sick leave for use    for the employee’s medical needs, those of a family member, or to address    incidents of domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</item></row5><row6 is_array="true"><item>The Working Families Flexibility    Act (2012, 2009)[38]</item><item>To allow workers to request    flexible work arrangements, and to require employers to consider requests (a    “right to request flexibility” policy).</item></row6><row7 is_array="true"><item>The Balancing Act of 2011</item><item>To enact a comprehensive    work-family support agenda, including FMLA expansion, child care support,    paid parental leave, paid sick leave, and workplace flexibility.</item></row7></data></result>
