<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://www.healthcare.gov" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
  <title>Health Insurance Blog - Healthcare.gov</title>
  
  <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog</link>
  <description>Health Insurance Blog</description>
  <language>en</language>
  
  <item>
    <title>Keep 2017 health coverage information current</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/2-tips-after-you-enrolled/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re enrolled in a 2017 health insurance plan, here’s what you need to know to get the full benefit of your health coverage and keep it up-to-date:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/after-youre-enrolled-tips.png&quot; title=&quot;{Report changes and pay your premium}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Man using 2 tips for 2017 Marketplace health insurance} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Activate your coverage &amp;amp; pay your first month’s premium &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must pay your first &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/premium&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;premium&lt;/a&gt; directly to the insurance company — not to the Health Insurance Marketplace. Your coverage won’t start until the insurance company gets your payment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insurance companies handle payments differently. Follow your insurer’s instructions about how and when to make your payment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/apply-and-enroll/complete-your-enrollment/&quot;&gt;paying your premium to complete your enrollment.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Update your income &amp;amp; household information if it changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reporting-changes/&quot;&gt;Report any life changes&lt;/a&gt; — like changes in income, household size, or residence, or other coverage offers — as soon as they happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These changes may affect your insurance coverage or savings and your taxes next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/2-tips-after-you-enrolled/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Don’t miss the deadline to file 2016 taxes &amp; report your health coverage!</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/beat-deadline-2016-taxes/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The April 18 tax filing deadline is less than one week away. No matter if you got your health coverage through the Marketplace, your job, or another source, you must report your 2016 coverage status to the IRS when you file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/beat-2016-tax-filing-deadline.png&quot; title=&quot;{Report tax filing status with 2016 return}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {2016 tax filing deadline is almost here} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;If you had a 2016 Marketplace plan with premium tax credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should have received tax &lt;a href=&quot;/tax-form-1095/&quot;&gt;Form 1095-A, Health Insurance Marketplace Statement&lt;/a&gt; in the mail. You can also get this form in your online Marketplace account. &lt;a href=&quot;/tax-form-1095/#find-1095-a&quot;&gt;See how to find it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your Form 1095-A to &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/reconcile&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;&quot;reconcile&quot;&lt;/a&gt; your health insurance tax credit on your return. If you used less premium tax credit than you qualify for, you'll get the difference as a credit. If you used more, you’ll pay the difference with your federal taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t file a 2016 tax return and reconcile, you could lose any advance payments of the premium tax credit beginning in 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Need tax help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out where to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/Individuals/Free-Tax-Return-Preparation-for-You-by-Volunteers&quot;&gt;free volunteer tax help&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/uac/Free-File:-Do-Your-Federal-Taxes-for-Free&quot;&gt;IRS Free File and related services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/uac/efile-with-commercial-software&quot;&gt;tax software program&lt;/a&gt; to help you prepare your taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/beat-deadline-2016-taxes/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>No 2017 health insurance? See if you can still get coverage</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/still-need-2017-health-insurance/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you didn’t enroll in Marketplace health insurance during the 2017 Open Enrollment Period, you may still be able to get coverage for the rest of 2017 two ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/still-need-2017-health-insurance.png&quot; title=&quot;{Get 2017 health insurance with a Special Enrollment Period}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Moving couple qualifies for health insurance for 2017} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2 ways to get covered for the rest of 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special Enrollment Periods:&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a certain type of life event — like losing health coverage, getting married, or having a baby — you may be able to enroll in a Marketplace plan for the rest of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/special-enrollment-period/&quot;&gt;Learn more about life events and Special Enrollment Periods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See if you qualify:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Answer a few quick questions to find out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may have to provide documentation to confirm the change that qualifies you for a Special Enrollment Period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medicaid and CHIP:&lt;/strong&gt; You can apply for free or low-cost coverage through Medicaid and CHIP any time, all year. If you qualify, you can enroll immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/getting-medicaid-chip/&quot;&gt;Learn more getting health insurance through Medicaid or CHIP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See if you qualify:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Select the second button, and answer a few questions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Start an application if you know you qualify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already know you qualify for a Special Enrollment Period, Medicaid, or CHIP, you can start an application now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/create-account&quot;&gt;Create an account for the first time&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;log in to an existing one&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/still-need-2017-health-insurance/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>2016 Tax Help: Get step-by-step instructions &amp; tax forms</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/2016-tax-help-forms/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;No matter how you got your 2016 health coverage — through the Marketplace, your job, or another source — you must report your 2016 health coverage status to the IRS when you file your 2016 taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2016-health-tax-form-help.png&quot; title=&quot;{File your 2016 taxes with correct health insurance form}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman filing taxes with 2016 health care tax forms} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you had 2016 Marketplace coverage, you’ll need Form 1095-A, Health Insurance Marketplace Statement, to &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/reconcile&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;“reconcile”&lt;/a&gt; your taxes. You should have received this form in the mail already. If you have an online account, Form 1095-A should be there too. If you didn’t receive a 1095-A, contact the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact-us/&quot;&gt;Marketplace Call Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For specific forms and step-by-step instructions, &lt;a href=&quot;/taxes/&quot;&gt;choose the situation that best applies to you&lt;/a&gt; to learn about health coverage and your 2016 federal taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get more tax help from the IRS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out where to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/Individuals/Free-Tax-Return-Preparation-for-You-by-Volunteers&quot;&gt;free volunteer tax help&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/uac/Free-File:-Do-Your-Federal-Taxes-for-Free&quot;&gt;IRS Free File and related services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/uac/efile-with-commercial-software&quot;&gt;tax software program&lt;/a&gt; to help you prepare your taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/2016-tax-help-forms/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Get the most out of your 2017 health insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/using-2017-coverage-for-health-care/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have 2017 Marketplace health insurance, check out 4 ways to stay healthy and get the care you need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/friends-understanding-health-coverage.png&quot; title=&quot;{Friends learning about prescription and preventive benefits}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Friends talking about health care} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understand your health coverage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The providers you can see and how much you pay out-of-pocket depend on which insurance plan you have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get your plan’s &quot;Summary of Benefits and Coverage&quot; from your insurance company or through the link in the plan description in your Marketplace account, and use it to review your plan’s covered benefits, cost sharing rules, and coverage limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Find a doctor in your plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most health plans give you the best deal on services when you see a doctor in the plan’s network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/using-marketplace-coverage/getting-medical-care/&quot;&gt;Learn the different ways to find a doctor who is in-network.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Learn about your prescription benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health plans will help pay the cost of certain prescription medicines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out which prescriptions your plan covers by visiting the insurance company’s website, calling them, reviewing the &quot;Summary of Benefits and Coverage,&quot; or reading materials that were mailed to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Take advantage of free preventive benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Marketplace health plans cover a set of preventive services at no cost to you, including some screenings, check-ups, patient counseling, and wellness services. You must use a provider in your plan’s network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/preventive-care-benefits/&quot;&gt;Check out the full list of covered services.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never had health insurance or have had a break in coverage, get more information about using your coverage and improving your health using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.cms.gov/outreach-and-education/downloads/c2c-roadmap.pdf&quot;&gt;Roadmap to Better Care and a Healthier You (PDF).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/using-2017-coverage-for-health-care/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Had 2016 Marketplace coverage? 3 tips when filing 2016 taxes</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/3-tips-for-filing-2016-taxes/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you enrolled in a Marketplace health insurance plan for 2016, you should have received tax &lt;a href=&quot;/tax-form-1095/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Form 1095-A, Health Insurance Marketplace Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the mail.  You also can get this form in your online Marketplace account, if you have one. You need this form to &quot;reconcile&quot; — meaning to find out if you used the right amount of premium tax credit during the year — your federal income taxes for 2016.  Here are 3 tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/1095-a-tax-tips-2016-taxes.png&quot; title=&quot;{Reconcile your 2016 federal taxes with these 3 tips}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Couple filing taxes using 3 tips for Marketplace health insurance and 2016 taxes} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Make sure your 1095-A is correct&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the instructions on the back and make sure everything is correct, including your &quot;monthly second lowest cost silver plan (SLCSP) premium.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need to make corrections, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact the Marketplace Call Center.&lt;/a&gt; We’ll send a corrected form. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t file your taxes until you get a correct 1095-A.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;2. Get Form 8962 to &quot;reconcile&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Print &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/f8962.pdf&quot;&gt;Form 8962 (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;. Note: If you’re using a tax software program to file, the form will trigger automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/i8962.pdf&quot;&gt;instructions from the IRS (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; on how to fill it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;3. Use your 1095-A to complete Form 8962&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See our &lt;a href=&quot;/taxes-reconciling/&quot;&gt;step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to enter your information from your 1095-A on Form 8962.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include your completed Form 8962 with your 2016 federal tax return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/3-tips-for-filing-2016-taxes/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>3 Tips: Marketplace insurance &amp; 2016 taxes</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/3-tips-for-health-insurance-and-2016-taxes/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;As you prepare to file your 2016 federal taxes, it’s important to know that reporting information about your health coverage is part of the tax filing process. If you had Marketplace health insurance in 2016, check out these 3 quick tax tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/3-tips-for-health-insurance-and-2016-taxes.png&quot; title=&quot;{Accurately prepare your 2016 federal taxes with these 3 tips}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman filing taxes using 3 tips for Marketplace health insurance and 2016 taxes} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Form 1095-A and &quot;reconciling&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look for Form 1095-A in the mail.&lt;/strong&gt; If anyone in your household had a Marketplace plan in 2016, we’ll mail you &lt;a href=&quot;/tax-form-1095/&quot;&gt;Form 1095-A, Health Insurance Marketplace Statement&lt;/a&gt; by early February. Check the information, and if everything is accurate, store it in a safe place with your other health insurance and tax forms. You’ll use it when you file your taxes. &lt;a href=&quot;/tax-form-1095/#find-1095-a&quot;&gt;If you have an online Marketplace account, it may be there too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you file, make sure your 1095-A is accurate.&lt;/strong&gt; If it’s not, contact the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact-us/&quot;&gt;Marketplace Call Center.&lt;/a&gt; Check things like your coverage, household, and premium information. If the form has errors, you can get a new one. If you file with the outdated form, you may need to file an amended tax return using your corrected 1095-A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be sure to &quot;reconcile.&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; If you had a Marketplace plan and used &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/advanced-premium-tax-credit&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;advanced payments of the premium tax credit&lt;/a&gt; to lower your monthly payment, you’ll have to &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/reconcile&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;&quot;reconcile&quot;&lt;/a&gt; these payments when you file your federal income taxes. You’ll use IRS Form 8962 to compare the amount of premium tax credit you used during the year (from Form 1095-A) with the premium tax credit you actually qualify for based on your final income. Any difference will affect your refund or tax owed. &lt;a href=&quot;/taxes-reconciling/&quot;&gt;Learn more about &quot;reconciling&quot;&lt;/a&gt; — and see a chart showing you how to use both forms to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Get step-by-step instructions &amp;amp; tax forms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details, &lt;a href=&quot;/taxes/&quot;&gt;choose the situation that best applies to you&lt;/a&gt; to learn about health coverage and your 2016 federal taxes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/3-tips-for-health-insurance-and-2016-taxes/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Attention: Time is running out for 2017 health coverage</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/avoid-2017-health-insurance-deadline/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Your last chance to enroll in or change Marketplace health insurance plans for 2017 is &lt;strong&gt;January 31, 2017.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s just over 2 weeks away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/avoid-2017-health-insurance-deadline.png&quot; title=&quot;{Don’t miss the January 31 deadline to update your 2017 health plan}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Young woman on phone updating her information to avoid health insurance deadline} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Act now &amp;amp; don’t miss the health insurance deadline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First time using HealthCare.gov?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;/create-account&quot;&gt;Create an account now.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Already have an account?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;Log in now&lt;/a&gt; to update or complete your application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;blockquote-important&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: Want your coverage to start February 1?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply and enroll by January 15, and your new plan will take effect February 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Already enrolled for 2017?  You can still change plans.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were automatically enrolled in a 2017 health plan, we strongly encourage you to &lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;log in&lt;/a&gt; and update your information. Updating your application with your expected 2017 income and household changes will help you get the right amount of savings. You’ll also have a chance to see if there are other health plans that may work better for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change plans until January 31, 2017. After that, you can enroll in or change 2017 plans only if you qualify for a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/avoid-2017-health-insurance-deadline/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Make your health a priority — Get Marketplace insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/new-year-new-health-insurance/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Ring in the New Year by getting Marketplace health insurance! You have until &lt;strong&gt;January 31, 2017&lt;/strong&gt; to apply for and enroll in affordable, quality Marketplace health coverage for the rest of 2017. If you enroll in health insurance by January 15, your new coverage can start February 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/start-new-year-with-marketplace-health-coverage.png&quot; title=&quot;{start-new-year-with-marketplace-health-coverage}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {New Year fireworks celebrating enrolling in Marketplace health insurance} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 reasons to sign up now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t miss out on routine care with cost savings.&lt;/strong&gt; All Marketplace health coverage plans cover the same set of &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/what-marketplace-plans-cover/&quot;&gt;essential health benefits&lt;/a&gt; (like emergency services, pregnancy and newborn care, and prescription drugs) and certain &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/preventive-care-benefits/&quot;&gt;preventive health services&lt;/a&gt; (like shots and screening tests) at no cost to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plans may cost less than you think.&lt;/strong&gt; For 2017 Marketplace health insurance, most people can find coverage with premiums from $50 to $100 per month after financial help. &lt;a href=&quot;/lower-costs/&quot;&gt;Are you one of them?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get peace of mind for you and your family.&lt;/strong&gt; Fixing a broken leg can cost up to $7,500, and the average cost of a 3-day hospital stay is around $30,000. No one plans to get sick or hurt, but health insurance gives you important financial protection just in case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Take action to apply and enroll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First time using HealthCare.gov?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/create-account&quot;&gt;Create an account now.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Already have an account?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;Log in now&lt;/a&gt; to update or complete your application, and compare plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/new-year-new-health-insurance/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>After you enroll in 2017 coverage, don’t forget to pay your monthly premium</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/how-to-pay-health-insurance-monthly-premium/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve submitted your Marketplace application and enrolled in a plan, but you’re not done yet. You must pay your first health insurance &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/premium&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;premium&lt;/a&gt; for your coverage to start. You make the payment to your health insurance company — not the Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/complete-enrollment-pay-premium.png&quot; title=&quot;{pay-for-health-insurance}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {woman-pays-premium} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When &amp;amp; how to pay for health insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you enroll, your insurer may contact you by phone, mail, or email with payment instructions. Health insurance companies handle payments differently, so follow their instructions closely. Take careful note of the date the payment is due, and be sure to make your payment by then. If you don’t meet the due date, you could lose your health coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about paying your premium, including if it was received, call your insurance company. You’ll see their phone number on your plan brochure, or you can go to their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understanding &amp;amp; using your new coverage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you complete your enrollment by paying your premium, you can use your new health coverage to help with medical costs for covered services like going to the doctor, filling prescriptions, and getting emergency care. To find out which prescriptions, doctors and other health care providers are covered through your new Marketplace plan, visit your health plan’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make sure you’re getting the most out of your new health insurance by understanding what you can do to &lt;a href=&quot;/using-marketplace-coverage/improving-your-health/&quot;&gt;stay healthy and get the care you need.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/how-to-pay-health-insurance-monthly-premium/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>It’s not too late: Update, shop &amp; switch plans through Jan 31</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/January-31-deadline-to-update-2017-health-coverage/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you had 2016 Marketplace coverage and didn’t re-enroll or change your health plan by December 15, the Marketplace probably enrolled you for 2017 health coverage in the same plan (or a similar one) based on information from your 2016 application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/update-compare-through-jan-31.png&quot; title=&quot;{Still time to update and compare}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Update compare at HealthCare.gov} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means you’ll have health coverage January 1. But the only way to make sure you have the right savings and the plan that’s best for you is to update your application and compare plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;blockquote-important&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: You can keep this plan or change until January 31&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can keep the plan you’ve been enrolled in or change to any other plan, even if your 2017 health care coverage has started.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Don’t miss out on the best plan &amp;amp; savings for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re happy with the 2017 health insurance plan you’re enrolled in, you should still update your information and compare plans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial help is based on your &lt;strong&gt;expected&lt;/strong&gt; 2017 income, not 2016. Updating your income and household information for 2017 is the only way to make sure you get the right amount of savings. If you don’t, you may owe money when you file your taxes or wind up paying higher monthly premiums during the year than you need to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New health care plans and prices that work better for you may be available this year. You’ll never know unless you update and compare for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;submit&quot; href='/login' class=&quot;btn btn-large btn-blue signup audience-btn left&quot;&gt;LOG IN TO UPDATE &amp;amp; COMPARE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New to HealthCare.gov?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/create-account&quot;&gt;Create an account&lt;/a&gt; and take your next steps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/January-31-deadline-to-update-2017-health-coverage/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Don’t miss the Dec 15 deadline for Jan 1 coverage!</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/sign-up-by-december-15/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is running out!  You only have until December 15, 2016 to sign up for or update your current Marketplace health insurance plan, so it’ll take effect January 1, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/beat-december-15-deadline.png&quot; title=&quot;{Update your information and enroll for Jan 1 coverage}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Reminder to sign up for or update your current plan by December 15 deadline} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 reasons to sign up now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t miss a day of being covered.&lt;/strong&gt; Enrolling by December 15 means you won’t have a break in health insurance between 2016 and 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plans may cost less than you think.&lt;/strong&gt;  About 85% of Marketplace consumers qualify for tax credits to help with costs. &lt;a href=&quot;/lower-costs/&quot;&gt;Are you one of them?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shopping and comparing will help you find your best option if you have a 2016 Marketplace plan.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you don’t act by December 15, the Marketplace will try to enroll you for January 1 based on information from your 2016 application, to make sure you don’t have a gap in coverage. But the only way to make sure you get the right amount of savings and find the best plan for you is to update your &lt;strong&gt;expected&lt;/strong&gt; 2017 income and household information, then compare plans. You may find new and more affordable plans for 2017, but you’ll never know unless you update and compare for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;How to enroll or update plans today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First time using HealthCare.gov?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/create-account&quot;&gt;Create an account now.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have 2016 Marketplace insurance or have an account?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;Log in now&lt;/a&gt; to update or complete your application and compare plans for 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/sign-up-by-december-15/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Don’t miss out on savings &amp; new plans: Update and compare by Dec 15</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/update-health-insurance/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have 2016 Marketplace insurance and want coverage for 2017, your best bet is to update your 2017 health insurance application with your expected income and household information for the year ahead – even if you want to keep the same plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update by December 15 and your changes take effect January 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/report-household-income-changes.png&quot; title=&quot;{Update your health insurance information today}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Reminder to update your health insurance information to get best plan &amp;amp; price} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why keep your information current&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you get the right amount of savings.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t update your application so your financial help is correct for 2017, you could wind up paying higher monthly health coverage &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/premium&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;premiums&lt;/a&gt; than you have to.  Or you might use more &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/advanced-premium-tax-credit&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;advance payments of the premium tax credit&lt;/a&gt; than you qualify for, so you’d have to pay the extra money back when you file your taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You may find 2017 plans that better meet your needs and budget.&lt;/strong&gt; Health care plans and prices change every year. Your situation may have changed too. Even if you don’t have any income or household updates to report, new and more affordable plans may be available to you.  You’ll never know if you don’t shop around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Ready to update your application?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt;, select your 2017 application. It’ll be pre-filled with your 2016 information, so you only need to update what’s changing. Update any expected income and household changes for 2017.  Then continue with your 2017 enrollment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t update your application and enroll in a plan by December 15, you may be automatically enrolled for 2017. This way, you’ll be covered January 1. &lt;strong&gt;But the only way to make sure you have a plan that works best for you, with the savings you qualify for, is to update your application and compare plans.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/update-health-insurance/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>How to protect yourself from &amp;#34;phishing&amp;#34; scams</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/protect-against-email-phishing-scams/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;When you enroll in Marketplace health insurance, we’ll send you emails from time to time. Unfortunately, there are some bad actors who may try to scam you with emails that look like they’re from the Marketplace, but are really trying to steal your information or infect your computer with a virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/protect-against-phishing-scams.png&quot; title=&quot;{Learn how to protect yourself from scams}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman protecting herself from phishing emails } &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Marketplace works closely with law enforcement to identify, prevent, stop, and prosecute these criminals, and we have strong systems in place to protect your information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a few important ways you can protect yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Look out for &quot;phishing&quot; emails&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;Phishing&quot; (or fraudulent) emails look like they’re from a trusted source and often contain links to a phony login page on a fake website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The subject lines may be threatening, or may promise some extraordinary benefit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They may contain bad grammar, spelling errors, and generic greetings, like &quot;Dear Customer.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The email address doesn’t match the official Marketplace email address, which is Marketplace@healthcare.gov or notices@healthcare.gov. Be sure the email address of any email that claims it’s from the Marketplace ends in &quot;.gov,&quot; as in HealthCare.gov.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;If you think you get a &quot;phishing&quot; email&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t click the links or download any attachments. They may have malicious code that will infect your computer with viruses or keystroke loggers that record what you type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t reply to the message. Instead, ignore or delete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you get an email that seems suspicious and you want to verify if you really have an issue you need to act on, visit HealthCare.gov. You can find out if the situation described in the email is accurate. &lt;a href=&quot;/contact-us/&quot;&gt;Contact the Marketplace Call Center&lt;/a&gt; if you still have questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never share any personal information by email. The Marketplace won’t ask you for your username, password, Social Security Number, or any bank account information by email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re concerned about your internet connection security, take a few minutes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST05-010&quot;&gt;learn how to make sure it’s secure.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;For more information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.us-cert.gov/ncas/tips/ST04-014&quot;&gt;protecting yourself against phishing scams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how the &lt;a href=&quot;/how-we-use-your-data/&quot;&gt;Marketplace uses and protects your information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/protect-against-email-phishing-scams/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Can you save on a 2017 Marketplace health plan?</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/save-on-health-insurance-with-2017-marketplace-plan/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to sign up for affordable, quality health insurance at HealthCare.gov. About 85% of Marketplace consumers qualify for tax credits to help with costs. Are you one of them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/85-percent-qualify-for-tax-credit-savings.png&quot; title=&quot;{See if you qualify for tax credit savings on health insurance costs}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Group of people saving on health insurance costs with tax credit} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Plans may be cheaper than you think&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For 2017 Marketplace health insurance, most people can find a plan with premiums from $50 to $100 per month after financial help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The median deductible has gone down $900 from last year. This is the amount you have to pay yourself for most services before your plan starts to pay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if you want to keep the same plan, it’s important to update your information and shop around. Last year, people who switched plans saved an average of $500.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick check: See if you’ll save on a 2017 plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select your state and household size to find out if you may qualify for savings on 2017 Marketplace coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;submit&quot; href='/lower-costs/' class=&quot;btn btn-large btn-green signup audience-btn left&quot;&gt;WILL YOU SAVE?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Take action &amp;amp; apply&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First time using HealthCare.gov?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/create-account&quot;&gt;Create an account now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have 2016 Marketplace insurance?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;Log in to an existing account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt;  If you want your coverage to start January 1, 2017, you must enroll or change plans by December 15, 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/save-on-health-insurance-with-2017-marketplace-plan/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Enroll in 2017 health insurance coverage now!</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/enroll-in-2017-health-insurance-today/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The Health Insurance Marketplace is open for business!  Starting today, you can apply for 2017 health insurance coverage for the first time — or renew, change, or update your current health plan for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enroll-today-for-2017-health-care-coverage.png&quot; title=&quot;{Enroll today to get 2017 health insurance starting January 1}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {November 1 calendar showing to enroll in 2017 health insurance today} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to get 2017 health insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you enroll, you can &lt;a href=&quot;/see-plans/&quot;&gt;preview plans with personalized price estimates&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/lower-costs/&quot;&gt;find out if you may qualify for savings&lt;/a&gt; — most people do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re ready to fill out or update your application, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New to HealthCare.gov?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;/create-account&quot;&gt;Create an account&lt;/a&gt; and take your next steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a 2016 Marketplace plan?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;/login&quot;&gt;Log in&lt;/a&gt; and update your application with any household or income changes you expect for 2017. Even if you want to keep the same plan, we strongly encourage you to update your information to get the right amount of savings.  Plus, new and more affordable health plans may be available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: Act by December 15 for January 1 coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For coverage starting January 1, 2017, you must enroll or change plans by December 15, 2016.  &lt;a href=&quot;/quick-guide/dates-and-deadlines/&quot;&gt;See other key dates.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More on Open Enrollment 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a &lt;a href=&quot;/quick-guide/&quot;&gt;quick overview of the Health Insurance Marketplace with these tips&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn &lt;a href=&quot;/income-and-household-information/&quot;&gt;how to estimate your income&lt;/a&gt; for your application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See how to &lt;a href=&quot;/choose-a-plan/&quot;&gt;pick a plan&lt;/a&gt; that’s right for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/enroll-in-2017-health-insurance-today/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Preview 2017 plans &amp; prices now!</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/preview-2017-health-care-plans-and-prices/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Enrollment for 2017 health insurance starts on November 1, 2016.  To get a head start, you can preview 2017 plans with personalized price estimates right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/preview-2017-health-care-plans-and-prices.png&quot; title=&quot;{Preview health care plans &amp;amp; prices before 2017 Open Enrollment }&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Couple previewing 2017 health care plans and prices} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you have to do is answer a few brief questions about your estimated 2017 income and household to see the health insurance plans and estimated prices available to you for 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;submit&quot; href='/see-plans/' class=&quot;btn btn-large btn-green signup audience-btn left&quot;&gt;PREVIEW 2017 PLANS &amp;amp; PRICES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Premium estimates show any savings you may qualify for based on only the basic 2017 information you entered.  You’ll see the exact prices you’ll pay when you fill out or update your Marketplace application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More on 2017 Open Enrollment &amp;amp; plan estimation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;/quick-guide/dates-and-deadlines/&quot;&gt;dates &amp;amp; deadlines for 2017 coverage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href=&quot;/choose-a-plan/&quot;&gt;quick tips on how to pick a plan&lt;/a&gt; that’s right for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/preview-2017-health-care-plans-and-prices/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Open Enrollment deadlines: Enrollment starts November 1!</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/key-health-insurance-deadlines/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/open-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Open Enrollment&lt;/a&gt; for 2017 Marketplace health insurance is just a few weeks away.  Here are some important health care enrollment and other dates to remember:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/key-health-insurance-deadlines.png&quot; title=&quot;{Don’t miss important health insurance deadlines for 2017 Marketplace coverage}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Pinned note with key health insurance deadlines and dates to remember} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 1, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; Open Enrollment 2017 starts.  This is the first day you can enroll, re-enroll, or change health plans for 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 15, 2016:&lt;/strong&gt; You must enroll in or change health plans by this date for your health plan to start January 1, 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 1, 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; 2017 insurance starts if you enrolled or changed plans by December 15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 31, 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; Last day to enroll in or change a 2017 health plan. After this date, you can enroll or change plans only if you qualify for a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Get ready today for November 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use this &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.cms.gov/outreach-and-education/marketplace-application-checklist.pdf&quot;&gt;simple checklist (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; to gather documents you’ll need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a quick Marketplace overview with these &lt;a href=&quot;/quick-guide/&quot;&gt;Marketplace tips&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2017 health plans and prices will be available to preview shortly before Open Enrollment starts. Check back soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/key-health-insurance-deadlines/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>This Open Enrollment, don’t forget to compare 2017 Marketplace health plans</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/compare-health-insurance-for-open-enrollment-2017/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have 2016 Marketplace health insurance, you can renew, change, or update your plan for 2017 starting November 1, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/compare-health-insurance-for-oe-2017.png&quot; title=&quot;{Renew coverage, update info, compare health insurance plans &amp;amp; prices for 2017 health coverage}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Starting November 1, you can renew coverage, update info, compare health insurance plans &amp;amp; prices} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;blockquote-important&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: 2017 health insurance plan &amp;amp; price previews coming soon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 health plans and prices will be available for preview on HealthCare.gov shortly before November 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 reasons why it’s important to update and compare health coverage plans for 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Plans:&lt;/strong&gt;  New, affordable plans that meet your needs and budget may be available this year. You may find 2017 health plans that better meet your needs and budget — especially if you’ve had or expect income or household changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accurate Savings:&lt;/strong&gt; Your 2017 health care savings are based on your expected 2017 income, not last year’s.  If you don’t update your information, your premium tax credit and other savings could be wrong for 2017. This means you could wind up paying more for your monthly premium or owing when you file your taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Best Plan for You:&lt;/strong&gt; You may be automatically enrolled for 2017, but this may not be the best way to get a health insurance plan that works for you, with the right savings. If you don’t renew or enroll in a plan by December 15, 2016, you may be automatically enrolled in the same or a similar plan. Even if you want that plan, you should still update your information and see all the plans available to you for 2017. You can do this as soon as November 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/keep-or-change-plan/&quot;&gt;Get more information on renewing, changing, or updating your health plan for 2017.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/compare-health-insurance-for-open-enrollment-2017/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>5 tips to get ready for 2017 Marketplace Open Enrollment</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/prepare-for-2017-open-enrollment/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/open-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Open Enrollment&lt;/a&gt; for a 2017 Health Insurance Marketplace plan is almost here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/prepare-for-2017-open-enrollment.png&quot; title=&quot;{Prepare now for 2017 Open Enrollment starting November 1, 2016}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Man preparing for 2017 Open Enrollment to get health coverage} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting November 1, 2016, you can sign up for 2017 health insurance (with coverage starting as soon as January 1, 2017) at HealthCare.gov. That’s just about a month away!  You’ll be able to preview plans and prices for 2017 shortly before then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5 tips to prepare for 2017 Open Enrollment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a quick Marketplace overview.&lt;/strong&gt;  If you’re new to the Marketplace, &lt;a href=&quot;/quick-guide/&quot;&gt;this single health coverage overview page&lt;/a&gt; tells you what you need to know and provides links to more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mark key dates on your calendar.&lt;/strong&gt;  Learn about the &lt;a href=&quot;/quick-guide/dates-and-deadlines/&quot;&gt;key dates and deadlines&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you’re covered January 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure you have everything you’ll need to apply.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.cms.gov/outreach-and-education/marketplace-application-checklist.pdf&quot;&gt;Use this simple health care checklist (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; to gather the documents you’ll need to complete your application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay up-to-date with the latest health care information.&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;/subscribe/&quot;&gt;Sign up for email and text message reminders&lt;/a&gt; to get important health coverage information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn how to pick a health insurance plan that’s right for you.&lt;/strong&gt; Choosing a health plan can be complicated. &lt;a href=&quot;/choose-a-plan/&quot;&gt;Knowing just a few things before you compare plans&lt;/a&gt; can make it simpler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/prepare-for-2017-open-enrollment/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Take action: Flu season is almost here</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/preventive-health-flu-shot/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Flu season can start as early as October, so it’s important to be proactive and get the flu shot to protect yourself and your family from this potentially serious disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/stay-healthy-with-flu-shot.png&quot; title=&quot;{Protect yourself and your family from the flu with the flu vaccine }&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Stay healthy by getting a free flu shot} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CDC encourages mostly everyone 6 months and older to get the flu vaccine each year. Here are 3 reasons why you shouldn’t put it off:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s free.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a Marketplace health insurance plan, you can get the flu shot for free from a doctor or other provider in your plan’s network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It's easy.&lt;/strong&gt; You can get a flu shot at many convenient locations, like pharmacies and some grocery stores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll protect yourself and others.&lt;/strong&gt;  With a flu shot, you can reduce your chance of getting sick and spreading the flu to others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Get more information on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdc.gov/flu/&quot;&gt;protecting yourself from the flu.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Other advantages of Marketplace insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flu shots aren’t the only preventive benefit covered by Marketplace plans. They also cover a set of &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/preventive-care-benefits/&quot;&gt;preventive health care services&lt;/a&gt; — including some screenings, check-ups, patient counseling, and wellness services. These are all free when delivered by a network provider, so be sure to take advantage of them!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/preventive-health-flu-shot/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>3 ways to get information for 2017 health insurance coverage</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/getting-health-insurance-information/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;With 2017 Open Enrollment starting November 1, now is  a great time to sign up for reminders and updates from the Health Insurance Marketplace about 2017 coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/getting-health-insurance-information.png&quot; title=&quot;{Get updated health insurance information with email, text, social media}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Stay connected for health insurance information} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy — just enter some quick information to get reminders, and follow us on social media. After you’re signed up, we’ll tell you about upcoming changes, deadlines, and new features. Plus, we’ll let you know as soon as the health plans and prices for 2017 are available to preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 3 simple ways to stay connected and get health insurance information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/subscribe/&quot;&gt;Sign up for email and text reminders.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HealthCareGov&quot;&gt;Twitter.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Healthcare.gov&quot;&gt;Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/getting-health-insurance-information/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>3 simple tips to stay healthy with Marketplace insurance </title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/stay-healthy-with-marketplace-insurance/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting health insurance is an important first step to better health and well-being!  If you’ve gotten coverage, get the most out of your Marketplace health insurance plan and stay healthy throughout the year by following these simple tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/staying-healthy-with-your-marketplace-health-insurance.png&quot; title=&quot;{Tips to stay healthy using your Marketplace health insurance}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Stay healthy with your Marketplace health insurance  } &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 tips to a healthier you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice preventive care.&lt;/strong&gt; Staying healthy increases the chances you’ll be there for your family and friends for many years to come. Be sure to take advantage of the &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/preventive-care-benefits/&quot;&gt;free preventive services&lt;/a&gt; that come with your Marketplace plan and get your recommended health screenings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand what providers are covered by your health plan and where to go for care.&lt;/strong&gt; Some plan types allow you to use almost any doctor or health care facility. Others limit your choices or charge you more if you use providers outside their network. Check with your plan for more information on what providers you can use and what your costs will be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a doctor you can trust.&lt;/strong&gt; Choosing the right provider is one of the most important decisions you’ll make about your health care, and finding the right one can take a little work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For more information about using your health insurance and improving your health, visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.cms.gov/outreach-and-education/downloads/c2c-roadmap.pdf&quot;&gt;Coverage to Care Roadmap (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/stay-healthy-with-marketplace-insurance/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Start the school year strong with health insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/student-health-insurance-options/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;College is stressful enough, so give yourself the peace of mind that comes with having health insurance this school year.  Getting health insurance may be easier and cheaper than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/health-insurance-for-students.png&quot; title=&quot;{Don’t leave health insurance off back-to-school list}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Health-insurance-on-back-to-school-list} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a college student, you have several options available to you that count as &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/qualifying-health-coverage&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;&quot;qualifying health coverage&quot;&lt;/a&gt;. With a range of plan types and costs to choose from, it's not hard to find health insurance that works for your life and your budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Health insurance options for college students&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/young-adults/children-under-26/&quot;&gt;Coverage under your parent's insurance plan&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; You may be able to stay on your parent's health plan until you turn 26.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/young-adults/college-students/&quot;&gt;Student health plans&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; If your school offers a student health plan, it can be an easy and affordable way to get basic insurance coverage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/quick-guide/&quot;&gt;Marketplace health plans&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Starting on November 1, 2016, you can enroll in a Marketplace health insurance plan that covers &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/essential-health-benefits&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;essential health benefits&lt;/a&gt; and other benefits. If you're under 30, you can buy a &lt;a href=&quot;/choose-a-plan/plans-categories/#catastrophic&quot;&gt;Catastrophic health plan&lt;/a&gt; to protect yourself from worst-case scenarios, like getting seriously sick or injured.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/eligibility/&quot;&gt;Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/childrens-health-insurance-program/&quot;&gt;Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP)&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; When you apply for coverage through the Marketplace, you'll find out if you qualify for Medicaid or CHIP. If you qualify, your coverage can begin immediately, any time of year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Get more information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under 30? &lt;a href=&quot;/under-30/#/questions&quot;&gt;Get a customized decision guide&lt;/a&gt; that'll help you decide what's right for you, by answering a few fast questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/student-health-insurance-options/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Brushing up on how to use Marketplace dental insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/how-to-use-your-marketplace-dental-insurance/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;When you enrolled in Marketplace coverage, you may have chosen a health plan that included dental coverage or purchased a separate, stand-alone dental plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/how-to-use-your-marketplace-dental-insurance.png&quot; title=&quot;{See how to use your Marketplace dental coverage}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman using her Marketplace dental insurance} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to make sure you’re getting the most out of your dental insurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Know what services your dental plan covers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though many dental insurance plans cover common dental benefits — like fillings, cleanings, care to fix decayed or fractured teeth, and dentures — different plans cover different services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some dental plans only cover children and others cover families.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check with your dental insurance company to find out what’s exactly covered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Understand your out-of-pocket costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a high coverage level, you’ll have higher &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/premium&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;premiums&lt;/a&gt; but lower &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/co-payment&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;copayments&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/deductible&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;deductibles&lt;/a&gt;. So you'll pay more every month, but less when you use dental services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a low coverage level, you’ll pay less every month, but more when you get services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Find a dentist that’s right for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not all types of providers take all insurance plans or types of coverage. Call the office before you go to make sure they accept your coverage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you make your appointment, have your insurance card or other documentation handy and know what services you want to get.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;More advantages of having health insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your Marketplace plan also covers treatment for &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/pre-existing-conditions/&quot;&gt;pre-existing medical conditions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/preventive-care-benefits/&quot;&gt;preventive health benefits.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out the other &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/what-marketplace-plans-cover/&quot;&gt;advantages of health insurance&lt;/a&gt; you get with your Marketplace plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/how-to-use-your-marketplace-dental-insurance/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Have a pre-existing condition? Don’t worry, you’re covered with the Marketplace</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/insurance-with-pre-existing-medical-conditions/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Diabetic? Chronically sick? Don’t worry!  With Marketplace health insurance, your plan covers treatment for any &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/pre-existing-condition&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;pre-existing medical condition&lt;/a&gt; you had when you enrolled in coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/coverage-with-pre-existing-medical-condition.png&quot; title=&quot;{You’re covered for all pre-existing medical conditions}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Patient talking to doctor about treatment for pre-existing medical condition} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;You’re protected&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now that you’re enrolled, your health plan can’t deny you coverage, raise your rates, or refuse to pay for &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/what-marketplace-plans-cover/&quot;&gt;essential health benefits&lt;/a&gt;, just because you have a chronic or pre-existing medical condition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Women also can’t be charged more than men. If you were pregnant before you applied, your insurance plan can’t reject you or charge you more because of your pregnancy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;What this benefit means for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treatment for any pre-existing medical condition — like a disability, asthma, diabetes, or cancer — is covered from the day your coverage began. Pregnancy is covered from the day your plan starts too, even if you were pregnant before your coverage began.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketplace plans can’t put annual or lifetime limits on your coverage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Other benefits of having health insurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.cms.gov/outreach-and-education/downloads/c2c-roadmap.pdf&quot;&gt;Coverage to Care Roadmap (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; for more information on finding a provider you can trust to treat your pre-existing condition. You may need to see more than one type of provider, like a specialist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/pre-existing-conditions/&quot;&gt;getting health insurance with a pre-existing condition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take advantage of the &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/what-marketplace-plans-cover&quot;&gt;other health benefits&lt;/a&gt; available to you with your Marketplace plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/insurance-with-pre-existing-medical-conditions/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Take charge of your health with free Marketplace insurance benefits for women</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/marketplace-health-care-for-women/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that you have Marketplace health insurance, you have more ways to take charge of your health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/health-care-for-women.png&quot; title=&quot;{See all health care options for women}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Women huddled together talking about Marketplace health care for women} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Marketplace plan covers a long list of free preventive services for women — including mammograms, yearly well-woman doctor visits, and other screening tests.  All plans also cover other health care for women, like pregnancy and childbirth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Free preventive health care for women&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With your Marketplace coverage, you have access to several preventive services — like annual well-woman visits and genetic testing for breast cancer, if you’re at risk. These services are free when you go to a provider in the plan’s network, even before you’ve met your &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/deductible&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;deductible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See a full list of free &lt;a href=&quot;/preventive-care-women/&quot;&gt;preventive benefits for women&lt;/a&gt; that your Marketplace plan covers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Contraception&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketplace plans must cover FDA-approved contraceptive methods — including birth control pills — as prescribed by a health care provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out more about &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/birth-control-benefits/&quot;&gt;birth control benefits&lt;/a&gt; in the Marketplace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Pregnancy, childbirth &amp;amp; breastfeeding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both maternity care and childbirth are covered by all Marketplace plans — even if you’re pregnant before your health coverage starts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most Marketplace plans provide breastfeeding equipment and counseling for pregnant and nursing women. Your health insurance plan will cover the cost of a breast pump — either a rental or one you’ll keep, depending on your plan’s rules and provider recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get more information on &lt;a href=&quot;/what-if-im-pregnant-or-plan-to-get-pregnant/&quot;&gt;pregnancy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/breast-feeding-benefits/&quot;&gt;breastfeeding&lt;/a&gt; health care for women.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;More information on health insurance for women&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/what-marketplace-plans-cover/&quot;&gt;advantages of having health insurance&lt;/a&gt; and all &lt;a href=&quot;/preventive-care-women/&quot;&gt;free preventive health services&lt;/a&gt; available to women with Marketplace insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/marketplace-health-care-for-women/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Take advantage of free preventive health care with Marketplace insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/preventive-health-care-benefits/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that with a Marketplace health insurance plan &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/preventive-services&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;preventive services&lt;/a&gt; — like shots and screening tests — are covered at no cost to you? These free preventive services can help you stay healthy and save you money in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/understanding-preventive-care-benefits.png&quot; title=&quot;{Learn about all benefits of health insurance and preventive services}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Friends celebrating free preventive health care }&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you currently uninsured but want access to these benefits?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may be able to enroll in Marketplace coverage now if you qualify for a &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/your-options/&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t, you can apply for 2017 coverage during the next Open Enrollment Period starting November 1, 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Examples of covered preventive health services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are just some of the preventive benefits available to you and your family with Marketplace insurance:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For all adults:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screenings for blood pressure, diabetes, HIV, and certain cancers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colorectal cancer screenings (colonoscopies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/preventive-care-adults/&quot;&gt;See the full list of covered services for adults.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For women:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yearly well-woman visits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breastfeeding comprehensive support and counseling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FDA-approved contraception methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/preventive-care-women/&quot;&gt;See the full list of covered services for women.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For children:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular check-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immunization vaccines, including the flu shot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/preventive-care-children/&quot;&gt;See the full list of covered services for children.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; These services are free only when delivered by a doctor or other provider in your plan’s network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get more information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/what-marketplace-plans-cover/&quot;&gt;advantages of having health insurance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/preventive-health-care-benefits/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Understanding health insurance costs makes for better decisions</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/understanding-health-care-costs/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;When you buy a car, you probably think first about price — your monthly payment. But other expenses — like auto insurance, gas, and maintenance — can affect your wallet. Your total costs depend on which car you buy and the expenses that come with owning a car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health insurance can be like that. If you look only at your monthly payment, you may find that other costs have a big impact on your household budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/understanding-all-health-care-costs.png&quot; title=&quot;{Know about all health care costs such as deductibles, copayments, and premiums}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman considering all health care costs including premiums, deductibles, copayments}&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Total yearly costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s useful to think about your total yearly health insurance costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Premiums:&lt;/strong&gt; What you pay your insurance company every month — your &quot;monthly payment.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deductible:&lt;/strong&gt; The amount you have to pay before the insurance plan starts to pay its share. With a $900 deductible, you pay the first $900 of costs yourself. After that, the company starts to pay its share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copayments and coinsurance:&lt;/strong&gt; What you pay (a dollar amount or percentage of costs) when you get care after your insurance company starts paying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; All plans provide &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/preventive-care-benefits/&quot;&gt;free preventive care&lt;/a&gt; (including child checkups and vaccinations, well-woman visits, and more). And most plans cover some services before you hit your deductible, like discounted drugs, periodic checkups, and services to help you manage conditions like asthma or diabetes. You also get discounted prices from network providers from day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Your total yearly health insurance costs depend on how much care you use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t expect to use much care during the year, or if you have insurance mainly for protection against really high bills and for preventive care, looking mostly at your monthly premium may be right for you. You’ll pay a low premium but face high costs when you use care.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you expect to use regular care, or a lot of care, a plan with a &lt;strong&gt;higher&lt;/strong&gt; premium may be a better overall deal. Plans with higher premiums usually have lower deductibles, copayments, coinsurance, and out-of-pocket limits. So even if you pay more each month you may save money overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;We help you figure out your total health care costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you &lt;a href=&quot;/see-plans/&quot;&gt;preview plans and prices&lt;/a&gt; or shop for plans, you can pick a level of care you think you’ll need for the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you compare plans we’ll show you &quot;total estimated yearly costs&quot; — including premiums, deductibles, and copayments/coinsurance — for each one, based on the level of care you expect. Then you can compare the real costs of health insurance side-by-side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/choose-a-plan/your-total-costs/&quot;&gt;Get more information about your total health care costs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/understanding-health-care-costs/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Common Marketplace health insurance questions and answers</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/answers-to-your-questions/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about the Marketplace, don’t worry. Health insurance help is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/top-3-health-insurance-questions.png&quot; title=&quot;{Get answers to the most common health insurance questions}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman reading answers to common health insurance questions}&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For fast answers to your health care questions — whether they’re about managing your health insurance coverage, finding forms and documents, or understanding costs and savings — visit our &lt;a href=&quot;/get-answers/&quot;&gt;Get Answers&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 common questions answered&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I get health coverage now that Open Enrollment is over?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Enrollment for a 2016 plan is over, but you may still be able to enroll in 2016 health insurance 2 ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/special-enrollment-period/&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period (SEP)&lt;/a&gt; — like if you lose your health insurance, or have certain other life changes. Not sure you qualify for an SEP?  &lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Answer a few questions&lt;/a&gt; to find out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also apply for &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/getting-medicaid-chip/&quot;&gt;Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP)&lt;/a&gt; any time and can enroll immediately if you're eligible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If I don’t qualify for an SEP, Medicaid, or CHIP, when can I enroll next?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Open Enrollment Period for 2017 coverage is November 1, 2016 — January 31, 2017. &lt;a href=&quot;/subscribe/&quot;&gt;Sign up for emails&lt;/a&gt; to get deadline reminders and other important information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should I do if I get a notice asking me for documents to verify something on my application (like my income), or my eligibility for a Special Enrollment Period?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To avoid losing your health insurance and any savings you’ve been getting, you must submit document copies by the deadline in your notice. &lt;a href=&quot;/verify-information/&quot;&gt;Learn more here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Still need answers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sitemap/&quot;&gt;Browse all topics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/&quot;&gt;Visit our glossary&lt;/a&gt; for help with specific terms related to health coverage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tips-and-troubleshooting/&quot;&gt;Get application tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/contact-us/&quot;&gt;Give us a call&lt;/a&gt; to have your health insurance questions answered by a customer service representative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://localhelp.healthcare.gov&quot;&gt;Find someone in your area&lt;/a&gt; who may be able to meet with you in-person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/answers-to-your-questions/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Lose your health insurance? You may be able to enroll now</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/coverage-loss-for-special-enrollment-period/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you recently lost health insurance coverage, you may be able to enroll in Marketplace coverage with a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/does-my-coverage-loss-qualify-for-special-enrollment-period.png&quot; title=&quot;{Find out if your coverage loss qualifies for a special enrollment period}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman lost coverage and shops for new plans }&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Health insurance losses that may qualify for a Special Enrollment Period&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of job-based insurance:&lt;/strong&gt; You may qualify if your employer stopped offering health insurance, or you left a job where you had health coverage (even if you left by choice or were fired).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of individual health plan:&lt;/strong&gt; You may qualify if you’re no longer eligible for a student health plan, or your Marketplace plan is discontinued&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of eligibility for Medicaid or the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP):&lt;/strong&gt; You may qualify if you lose your eligibility because your income changed, making you ineligible for Medicaid, or if your child ages off CHIP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of eligibility for Medicare:&lt;/strong&gt; You may qualify if you become ineligible for premium-free Medicare Part A.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of coverage through a family member’s plan:&lt;/strong&gt; You may qualify if you turn 26 and can no longer be on a parent’s plan, or lose health coverage through a spouse due to a divorce, legal separation, or through the death of a family member.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;See if you qualify for Special Enrollment Period&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer a few questions to find out if you qualify for a Special Enrollment Period. We’ll also tell you if you may qualify for Medicaid or CHIP, which you can enroll in any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;submit&quot; href='/screener/' class=&quot;btn btn-large btn-blue signup audience-btn left&quot;&gt;SEE IF YOU QUALIFY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/special-enrollment-period/&quot;&gt;applying with a Special Enrollment Period.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/coverage-loss-for-special-enrollment-period/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Can you enroll in health insurance now?</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/qualify-for-special-enrollment-period/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you recently lost other health coverage, moved to a new home in a new ZIP code or county, gotten married, or had a baby? When big changes happen in life, you may be able to enroll in Marketplace health insurance right away with a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/do-i-qualify-for-special-enrollment-period.png&quot; title=&quot;{Quickly find out if you qualify for a special enrollment period}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Woman wondering if she qualifies for a special enrollment period}&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the button below, and answer a few questions about your major life change to find out if you qualify for a Special Enrollment Period:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;submit&quot; href='/screener/' class=&quot;btn btn-large btn-green signup audience-btn left&quot;&gt;SEE IF YOU QUALIFY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you qualify for a Special Enrollment Period, you’ll have 60 days from the life event to enroll. When you apply, you’ll also find out if you qualify for &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/getting-medicaid-chip/&quot;&gt;Medicaid or the Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP)&lt;/a&gt;. If you do, coverage can start the day you apply or earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;blockquote-important&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/strong&gt;
    When you apply, you must attest that the information you provide on the application is true, including the facts that qualify you for a Special Enrollment Period. You may be asked to &lt;a href=&quot;/verify-information/&quot;&gt;submit documents&lt;/a&gt; that prove your eligibility to enroll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;If you already think you qualify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start an application for Marketplace health insurance by visiting the &lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;screener landing page&lt;/a&gt; and selecting the third button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/special-enrollment-period/&quot;&gt;applying with a Special Enrollment Period.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/qualify-for-special-enrollment-period/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Retired? You have health insurance options </title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/retiree-health-insurance-options/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you recently retired and aren’t eligible for Medicare yet, you may be able to get health insurance through the Health Insurance Marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets//retiree-health-insurance.png&quot; title=&quot;{Get retiree health coverage if newly retired}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: { Friends happy about their retiree health insurance} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While retiring from a job alone doesn’t qualify you for a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;, losing health insurance does. If you lost health insurance when you retired, you have 60 days to enroll in a health plan outside Open Enrollment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you lose job-based insurance you may be offered &lt;a href=&quot;/unemployed/cobra-coverage/&quot;&gt;COBRA&lt;/a&gt; continuation coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you decide not to take COBRA coverage, you can enroll in a Marketplace plan instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’ve already started COBRA coverage, you have different options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you have retiree health insurance but want to buy a Marketplace plan instead, you can. But you won’t be able to get &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/premium-tax-credit&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;premium tax credits&lt;/a&gt; and other savings in the Marketplace. If you voluntarily drop your retiree health coverage, you don’t qualify for a Special Enrollment Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Apply with a Special Enrollment Period&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Answer a few quick questions&lt;/a&gt; to see if you may qualify for a Special Enrollment Period or for Medicaid or CHIP.  We’ll tell you your next steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Already know you qualify? &lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Go to the Start Page&lt;/a&gt; and select the third button to start an application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;  Losing health coverage isn’t the only life event that qualifies you to enroll in a plan outside the Open Enrollment Period. You may also be eligible if you’ve had other life changes — like getting married, moving, or adopting a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More health coverage options for retirees&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out more about &lt;a href=&quot;/retirees/&quot;&gt;health insurance options for retirees.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have Medicare? Learn about &lt;a href=&quot;/medicare/medicare-and-the-marketplace/&quot;&gt;Medicare and the Marketplace.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/retiree-health-insurance-options/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Having a baby? You may be able to get or change health insurance outside Open Enrollment</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/health-insurance-having-a-baby/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you recently had or adopted a baby, you may qualify for a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;. This means you can apply and enroll in or change Marketplace health plans outside Open Enrollment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/affordable-family-health-insurance-after-birth.png&quot; title=&quot;{Baby may qualify for special enrollment period}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Couple having baby and qualifying for affordable family health insurance} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you enroll in a plan during a Special Enrollment Period, your new health coverage can begin the day your baby is born — even if you enroll in the plan up to 60 days afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Apply with a Special Enrollment Period&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Answer a few quick questions&lt;/a&gt; to see if you’re likely to qualify for a Special Enrollment Period or for Medicaid or CHIP.  We’ll tell you your next steps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Already know you qualify? &lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Go to the Start Page&lt;/a&gt; and select the third button to start an application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;More on Special Enrollment Periods&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a baby isn’t the only &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/qualifying-life-event&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;life event&lt;/a&gt; that qualifies you to enroll in a plan outside the Open Enrollment Period. You may also be eligible if you’ve had other life changes — like getting married, moving, or losing coverage you had from a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/special-enrollment-period/&quot;&gt;getting coverage outside Open Enrollment.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/health-insurance-having-a-baby/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Attention: Report household and income changes to the Marketplace</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/report-major-life-changes-to-marketplace/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have a Marketplace health plan and your &lt;a href=&quot;/reporting-changes/which-changes-to-report/&quot;&gt;income or household has recently changed&lt;/a&gt;, you should report the major life change as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/report-household-and-income-changes.png&quot; title=&quot;Report income changes and other household changes as soon as possible&quot; alt=&quot;Image: Reminder to report major life changes to the marketplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major life changes — like higher or lower income, adding or losing household members, or getting other health coverage — may affect the health insurance or savings you’re eligible for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t report changes, you could wind up owing more — or less — when you file your next federal tax return. Avoid surprises by keeping your information up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why you should report changes to the Marketplace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You may qualify for more savings than you’re getting now&lt;/strong&gt; if your income goes down or you gain a household member. This could lower what you pay in monthly premiums. You also could qualify for &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/getting-medicaid-chip/&quot;&gt;Medicaid or CHIP coverage&lt;/a&gt; and could continue to pay more than you need to for a Marketplace plan by not reporting the change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You may qualify for less savings than you’re getting now&lt;/strong&gt; if your income goes up or you lose a member of your household. If you don’t report the income change, you could wind up having to pay money back when you file your federal tax return for the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want a better idea of how your savings may change?&lt;/strong&gt; Use this tool from the IRS to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.taxpayeradvocate.irs.gov/estimator/premiumtaxcreditchange/&quot;&gt;estimate how your premium tax credit will change&lt;/a&gt; if your income or family size change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to report income changes or other major life changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can report changes to the Health Insurance Marketplace 3 ways:  online, by phone, or with in-person help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/reporting-changes/how-to-report-changes/&quot;&gt;Find out how to report changes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/report-major-life-changes-to-marketplace/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Planning a move? You and your family may be able to enroll in health insurance</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/health-insurance-options-after-move/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;If you or your family are moving (or have moved in the past 60 days), you may still be able to enroll in affordable family health insurance this year through a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/affordable-family-health-insurance-after-move.png&quot; title=&quot;{Moving may qualify for special enrollment period}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Couple moving and qualifying for affordable family health insurance} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;blockquote-important&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT&lt;/strong&gt;
Starting July 2016, in most cases, you must prove you had &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/minimum-essential-coverage&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;qualifying health coverage&lt;/a&gt; for one or more days during the 60 days before your move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on where you move, new health care options, prices, and savings may be available to you. In most cases, you’ll have 60 days from your move date to enroll in new coverage or change plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Moves that qualify for a Special Enrollment Period&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moving to a new home in a new ZIP code or county&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moving to the U.S. from a foreign country or United States territory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A student moving to or from the place they attend school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A seasonal worker moving to or from the place they both live and work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moving to or from a shelter or other transitional housing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Not sure if you qualify?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just &lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;answer a few quick questions&lt;/a&gt; to find out.  If you already know you qualify, &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/special-enrollment-period/#how-to-apply&quot;&gt;learn how to apply.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving isn’t the only &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/qualifying-life-event&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;life event&lt;/a&gt; that qualifies you to enroll in a plan outside the Open Enrollment Period. You may also be eligible if you’ve had other life changes — like getting married, having or adopting a baby, or losing coverage you had from a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage-outside-open-enrollment/special-enrollment-period/&quot;&gt;getting coverage outside Open Enrollment.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/health-insurance-options-after-move/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Using your Marketplace insurance to keep you healthy</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/3-steps-to-use-health-insurance-to-stay-healthy/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting health insurance is an important first step to better health. Now that you’re covered, here are 3 ways to get the most out of your health plan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/patient-doctor-discuss-preventive-care-benefits.png&quot; title=&quot;{Find a doctor to use health insurance and stay healthy}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Patient and doctor discussing preventive health care benefits} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Find a provider you trust&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if you don’t need care right now, it’s important to find a doctor you can trust and work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You usually get the best deal if you &lt;a href=&quot;/using-marketplace-coverage/getting-medical-care/&quot;&gt;choose someone in your network&lt;/a&gt;. If you see doctors outside your network, you might pay more or get no coverage at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find a doctor in your health coverage plan, or to see if your current doctor is in-network, visit your health plan’s website and check their provider directory. Then call the doctor directly to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understand your deductible&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your health insurance deductible is the amount you owe for most covered health care services before your plan begins to pay its share. If your deductible is $250, you pay $250 in medical costs yourself, and after that you pay just a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/co-payment&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;copayment&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/co-insurance&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;coinsurance&lt;/a&gt;. If your deductible is $3,000, that’s how much you’ll pay yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to learn which services in your plan aren’t subject to your health insurance deductible. Some plans provide primary care visits for just a copayment before you meet your deductible; others offer discounts on drugs, including generic drugs. Some offer free disease management programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read your plan materials carefully to see what services are covered before you meet your deductible. Call your insurance company if you have questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Use your preventive health services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Marketplace plans cover recommended &lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/preventive-care-benefits/&quot;&gt;preventive health care&lt;/a&gt; before you meet your deductible and at no cost to you, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancer screenings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immunizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/birth-control-benefits/&quot;&gt;Contraceptive services for women&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well-child visits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annual well-woman visit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular pediatric services, including all shots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/coverage/breast-feeding-benefits/&quot;&gt;Breastfeeding benefits&lt;/a&gt; for pregnant and nursing women&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For more tips on how to use your new coverage, visit our &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.cms.gov/outreach-and-education/downloads/c2c-roadmap.pdf&quot;&gt;Coverage to Care Roadmap (PDF).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/3-steps-to-use-health-insurance-to-stay-healthy/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Graduating? You have health insurance options</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/health-insurance-options-for-graduates/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats, graduates! Whether you’re heading into the working world or planning your next move, you have options for affordable health insurance that works for your life and your budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets//health-insurance-options-for-graduates.jpg&quot; title=&quot;{Know your health insurance options as a recent graduate}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Graduate holding sign saying he has young adult health insurance coverage} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Find your best options fast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under 30?  Just answer a few quick questions to get a personalized guide that’ll help you make a good coverage decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a type=&quot;submit&quot; href='/under-30/#/questions/' class=&quot;btn btn-large btn-green signup audience-btn left&quot;&gt;SEE OPTIONS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 health insurance options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may get insurance from your job, but if you don’t, you still have options for health coverage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under 26?  Stay or get covered on a parent’s health insurance plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may be able to get added to or stay &lt;a href=&quot;/young-adults/children-under-26/&quot;&gt;covered under a parent’s health insurance plan&lt;/a&gt; until you turn 26 — even if you’re married, not living at home, financially independent, or have an offer of insurance through a job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy your own health insurance plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may be able to buy your own plan through the Health Insurance Marketplace. If you’re just starting out and not making much money, you’ll probably qualify for &lt;a href=&quot;/young-adults/ready-to-apply/&quot;&gt;savings&lt;/a&gt; — which may make your monthly health insurance bill less than your cell phone bill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You also can choose a &lt;a href=&quot;/choose-a-plan/plans-categories/#catastrophic&quot;&gt;&quot;Catastrophic&quot; health plan&lt;/a&gt; — an affordable way to protect yourself from worst-case scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outside the yearly &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/open-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Open Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;, you can enroll only if you have a life change that qualifies you for a &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/special-enrollment-period&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Special Enrollment Period&lt;/a&gt;. Turning 26 and dropping off a parent’s insurance plan, losing health insurance for any other reason, getting married, or having a baby are just a few changes that let you enroll in the off-season.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;See if you qualify for a Special Enrollment Period.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get coverage through Medicaid or CHIP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In some states, Medicaid &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/medicaid-expansion-and-you/&quot;&gt;covers all adults below a certain income level&lt;/a&gt;. If you qualify, you can enroll any time. &lt;a href=&quot;/lower-costs/&quot;&gt;See if this applies to your income and your state.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In all states, &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/&quot;&gt;Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP)&lt;/a&gt; provide health coverage for some individuals, families and children, pregnant women, and people with disabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t have any health coverage you may have to &lt;a href=&quot;/fees/fee-for-not-being-covered/&quot;&gt;pay a penalty&lt;/a&gt;. There’s no special exception for age or student status.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/health-insurance-options-for-graduates/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Get Medicaid &amp; Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP) health insurance any time</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/medicaid-chip-health-insurance-any-time/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Enrollment for a 2016 Marketplace health insurance plan is over.  But if you qualify for &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/medicaid&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Medicaid&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;/glossary/childrens-health-insurance-program-chip&quot; title=&quot;glossary&quot;&gt;Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP)&lt;/a&gt;, you can get health insurance any time of year, with coverage starting immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/medicaid-chip-health-insurance-options-2016.png&quot; title=&quot;{Medicaid and CHIP available all year to qualified enrollees}&quot; alt=&quot;Image: {Family happy to have Medicaid or CHIP coverage from Obamacare} &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What are Medicaid and CHIP?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medicaid provides coverage for some low-income people, families and children, pregnant women, the elderly, and people with disabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some states have expanded their Medicaid programs to cover all people below certain income levels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CHIP provides low-cost health coverage to children in families that earn too much money to qualify for Medicaid. In some states, CHIP covers parents and pregnant women too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Find out if you qualify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/screener/&quot;&gt;Visit our screener&lt;/a&gt;, select the second option &quot;See if you may qualify for Medicaid or CHIP,&quot; and answer a few quick questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Already know you qualify?&lt;/strong&gt; You can apply for Medicaid and CHIP 2 ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By completing a &lt;a href=&quot;/get-coverage/&quot;&gt;health insurance application&lt;/a&gt; at HealthCare.gov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By applying directly to your &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/getting-medicaid-chip/#howtoapply&quot;&gt;state Medicaid agency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/medicaid-chip/getting-medicaid-chip/&quot;&gt;qualifying for Medicaid and CHIP.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/medicaid-chip-health-insurance-any-time/</guid>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>National Small Business Week: Keeping small businesses healthy</title>
    <link>https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/national-small-business-week-shop-coverage/</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s National Small Business Week.  As we recognize and celebrate the contributions small businesses make — like job creation, innovation, and global competitiveness — it’s important to think about health care options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/small-business-health-insurance.png&quot; title=&quot;Health insurance options for small businesses&quot; alt=&quot;Image: Small business owner offering affordable health insurance to employees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re the owner of a business with fewer than 50 full-time equivalent employees, you have choices that can make insurance more affordable, flexible, and easy to enroll in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Small Business Health Options Program can help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Small Business Health Options Program (also known as SHOP) can help your small business offer quality health insurance that meets your employees’ needs and stays within budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5 benefits of SHOP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to tax credits:&lt;/strong&gt;  Buying coverage through the SHOP Marketplace is the only way for you to take advantage of the Small Business Health Care Tax Credit. The smallest employers can save 50% of the cost of their premiums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control over costs:&lt;/strong&gt; The SHOP Marketplace lets you decide up front how much to contribute to premiums.  Plans can’t charge higher premiums because of higher medical costs or pre-existing conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year-round enrollment:&lt;/strong&gt; You generally can sign up for coverage any month of the year.  So it’s easy to offer employees insurance when it’s right for the business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible coverage options:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a variety of plans available. You can let your employees choose among several (if they want to) so employees can select a plan that‘s right for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support:&lt;/strong&gt; Get in-person assistance from agents and brokers or trained navigators. They can help make the buying process even simpler. You can also contact the SHOP Call Center at 1-800-706-7893 (TTY: 711) weekdays from 9 a.m. to 7 p.m. ET.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Get more information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a &lt;a href=&quot;/small-businesses/provide-shop-coverage/shop-marketplace-overview/&quot;&gt;quick overview of the SHOP Marketplace.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more information and resources for your small business, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sba.gov/nsbw&quot;&gt;National Small Business Week website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you a small business owner but with no employees? Learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;/self-employed/&quot;&gt;health care options if you’re self-employed.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <dc:creator>Healthcare.gov</dc:creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.healthcare.gov/blog/national-small-business-week-shop-coverage/</guid>
  </item>
  
</channel>
</rss>
